A Guide to the Papers of the Virginia Quarterly Review, 1935-1954
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Virginia Quarterly Review 1935-1954
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-24/3/1.561
This collection consists of 60 linear feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift of the editor on December 1956.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists of editorial correspondence with contributors during the tenure of the following editors: Stringfellow Barr (1931-1937); Lambert Davis (1937-1938); Lawrence Lee (1938-1942); Archibald Bolling Shepperson (1942); and, Charlotte Kohler (1942-1974). Included are almost all of the literary figures of this period, and many from other fields. Authors' original manuscripts together with proofs of almost every article and book review published in the Virginia Quarterly Review during this period. Proofs and manuscripts are filed in a separate sequence, chronologically by date of publication. A slip list of proofs and manuscripts is available in Special Collections.
Arrangement
Correspondence is filed alphabetically. Proofs and manuscripts are individually foldered and filed in a separate sequence, chronologically by date of publication.
Additional Descriptive Data
Other Finding Aid
A slip list of proofs and manuscripts is available in the Special Collections Department.
Contents List
- Volume I, 1925 April (Box 1)
- Volume I, 1925 July (Box 2)
- Volume I, 1925 October (Box 3)
- Volume II, 1926 January-April (Box 4)
- Volume II, 1926 April (Box 5)
- Volume II, 1926 July-October (Box 6)
- Volume II, 1926 October (Box 7)
- Volume III, 1927 January (Box 8)
- Volume III, 1927 April (Box 9)
- Volume III, 1927 July (Box 10)
- Volume III, 1927 October (Box 11)
- Volume IV, 1928 January (Box 12)
- Volume IV, 1928 April (Box 13)
- Volume IV, 1928 July (Box 14)
- Volume IV, 1928 October (Box 15)
- Volume V, 1929 January-April (Box 16)
- Volume V, 1929 July-October (Box 17)
- Volume VI, 1930 January-April (Box 18)
- Volume VI, 1930 July-October (Box 19)
- Volume VII, 1931 January- April (Box 20)
- Volume VII, 1931 July-October (Box 21)
- Volume VIII, 1932 January-April (Box 22)
- Volume VIII, 1932 July-October (Box 23)
- Volume IX, 1933 January-April (Box 24)
- Volume IX, 1933 July-October (Box 25)
- Volume X, 1934 January- April (Box 26)
- Volume X, 1934 July-October (Box 27)
- Volume XI, 1935 January-April (Box 28)
- Volume XI, 1935 July-October (Box 29)
- Volume XII, 1936 January-April (Box 30)
- Volume XII, 1936 July-October (Box 31)
- Volume XIII, 1937 Spring-Summer (Box 32)
- Volume XIII, 1937 Autumn-Winter (Box 33)
- Volume XIV, 1938 Spring-Winter (Box 34)
- Volume XIV, 1938 Summer-Autumn (Box 35)
- Volume XV, 1939 Spring-Summer (Box 36)
- Volume XV, 1939 Autumn-Winter (Box 37)
- Volume XVI, 1940 Spring-Summer (Box 38)
- Volume XVI, 1940 Autumn-Winter (Box 39)
- Volume XVII, 1941 Spring-Summer (Box 40)
- Volume XVII, 1941 Autumn-Winter (Box 41)
- Volume XVIII, 1942 Spring-Summer (Box 42)
- Volume XVIII, 1942 Autumn-Winter (Box 43)
- Volume XIX, 1943 Spring-Summer (Box 44)
- Volume XIX, 1943 Autumn-Winter (Box 45)
- Volume XX, 1944 Spring-Summer (Box 46)
- Volume XX, 1944 Autumn-Winter (Box 47)
- Volume XXI, 1945 Spring-Summer (Box 48)
- Volume XXI, 1945 Autumn-Winter (Box 49)
- Volume XXII, 1946 Spring-Summer (Box 50)
- Volume XXII, 1946 Autumn-Winter (Box 51)
- Volume XXIII, 1947 Spring-Summer (Box 52)
- Volume XXIII, 1947 Autumn-Winter (Box 53)
- Volume XXIV, 1948 Spring-Summer (Box 54)
- Volume XXIV, 1948 Autumn-Winter (Folder 55)
- Volume XXV, 1949 Spring-Summer (Box 56)
- Volume XXV, 1949 Autumn-Winter (Box 57)
- Volume XXVI, 1950 Spring-Summer (Box 58)
- Volume XXVI, 1950 Autumn-Winter (Box 59)
- Volume XXVII, 1951 Spring-Summer (Box 60)
- Volume XXVII, 1951 Autumn-Winter (Box 61)
- Volume XXVIII, 1952 Spring-Summer (Box 62)
- Volume XXVIII, 1952 Autumn-Winter (Box 63)
- Volume XXIX, 1953 Spring-Summer (Box 64)
- Volume XXIX, 1953 Autumn-Winter (Box 65)
- Volume XXX, 1954 Spring-Summer (Box 66)
- Volume XXX, 1954 Autumn-Winter (Box 67)
- Volume XXXI, 1955 Spring-Summer (Box 68)
- Volume XXXI, 1955 Autumn-Winter (Box 69)
- Miscellaneous Proofs, n.d. (Box 70)
- Clippings, 1931 (Box 70)
- Reviews not published, 1953 (Box 70)
- Railway Express Agency Shipper's Collect Receipts, ca. 1941 (Box 70)
- Abbe, George 1936-1954, 57 items (Box 71)
  Correspondence with Virginia Quarterly Review
- Abernethy, Thomas Perkins 1936-1954, 25 items (Box 71)
- Acheson, Dean 1954, 2 items (Box 71)
- Ackerson, John Thaddeus 1942-1954, 21 items (Box 71)
- Adams, Agatha 1950, 2 items (Box 71)
- Adams, James Donald 1935-1939, 3 items (Box 71)
- Adams, James Truslow 1932-1945, 14 items (Box 71)
- Adams, Leonie 1939-1947, 2 items (Box 71)
  Letters, Virginia Quarterly Review to Adams
- Adams, Robert Martin 1950-1954, 21 items (Box 71)
- A F G Agency 1937-1949, 19 items (Box 71)
- Agar, Herbert 1936-1953, 45 items (Box 71)
- Aiken, Conrad 1932-1954, 27 items (Box 71)
- Alcestis Press 1936-1937, 9 items (Box 71)
- Alderman, Edwin, Anderson 1929-1930, 2 items (Box 71)
  Letters, Virginia Quarterly Review to Alderman
- Aldington, Hilda 1952, 3 items (Box 71)
- Aldridge, John 1952-1953, 12 items (Box 71)
- Alexander, Holmes 1936-1938, 6 items (Box 71)
- Alexander, Sidney 1938-1951, 20 items (Box 71)
- Aley, Ruth 1937-1945, 14 items (Box 71)
- Algren, Nelson November 8, 1 l. (Box 71)
  Letter to Virginia Quarterly Review
- Alinsky, Saul 1943 April 5, 1 l. (Box 71)
- Allen, Frederick Lewis 1953, 3 items (Box 71)
- Allen, Hervey 1927-1948, 5 items (Box 71)
- Allen, Lafe Franklin 1947-1949, 14 items (Box 71)
- Allen, Robert S. 1935-1936, 3 items (Box 71)
- Allen, Sara Van Alstyne 1937-1942, 14 items (Box 71)
- Altick, Richard 1937-1952, 15 items (Box 71)
- The American Scholar 1941-1952, 21 items (Box 71)
- Anderson, Ellen 1945, 2 items (Box 71)
- Anderson, Mrs. Maxwell 1950, 2 items (Box 71)
- Anderson, Paul 1946, 7 items (Box 71)
- Anderson, Mr. & Mrs. Sherwood 1939-1941, 5 items (Box 71)
- Andrews, F. Emerson 1936-1951, 21 items (Box 71)
- Andrews, George Lawrence 1936-1942, 22 items (Box 71)
- Andrews, John Williams 1940-1947, 15 items (Box 71)
- Angell, Norman 1939, 5 items (Box 71)
- Anthony, George 1943-1950, 16 items (Box 71)
- Applebaum, Harold 1946-1948, 4 items (Box 71)
  Letters to Virginia Quarterly Review
- D. Appleton & Co. 1926, 2 items (Box 71)
- D. Appleton-Century Co. 1936-1947, 16 items (Box 71)
- Appleton-Century-Crofts, Inc. 1951, 3 items (Box 71)
- Armstrong, Hamilton 1954, 2 items (Box 71)
- Arnall, Ellis 1946-1954, 9 items (Box 71)
- Arnold, Thurman 1938-1946, 6 items (Box 71)
- Arrow Editions 1936-1940, 5 items (Box 71)
- Asch, Nathan 1946 June 19, 1 l. (Box 71)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Asch
- Astor, Vicountess Nancy 1935-1939, 14 items (Box 71)
- Duchess of Atholl 1938, 4 items (Box 71)
- Atkinson, Brooks 1947, 2 items (Box 71)
- Auchincloss, Louis 1946-1950, 5 items (Box 71)
- Auden, Wystan Hugh 1939-1946, 3 items (Box 71)
- Augur, Helen 1941, 8 items (Box 71)
- Authors' and Publishers' Service 1947-1950, 17 items (Box 71)
- Avrett, Robert 1937-1952, 16 items (Box 71)
- Miscellaneous A 1935-1955, ca. 800 items (Box 72)
  Miscellnaneous authors, Correspondence with Virginia Quarterly Review.
- Bacon, Leonard 1950-1953, 6 items (Box 73)
- Bainbridge, John 1944, 2 items (Box 73)
- Baker, Carlos 1945-1952, 58 items (Box 73)
- Baker, Ray Stanard 1942, 2 items (Box 73)
- Baker, Richard 1948-1954, 16 items (Box 73)
- Balch, Emily Clark 1938, 2 items (Box 73)
- Baldensperger, Fernand 1938-1940, 37 items (Box 73)
- Baldwin, Hanson 1942-1954, 42 items (Box 73)
- Baldwin, Roger 1938 March 17, 1 item (Box 73)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Baldwin
- Baldwin, Summerfield 1936, 3 items (Box 73)
- Ball, Joseph 1944, 2 items (Box 73)
- Ballard, Julia Brooke 1942-1954, 9 items (Box 73)
- Balz, Albert 1953, 5 items (Box 73)
- Bardin, James 1938, 4 items (Box 73)
- Bareau, Paul 1949, 7 items (Box 73)
- Barker, George 1947-1953, 6 items (Box 73)
- Barnes, Harry Elmer 1935-1940, 20 items (Box 73)
- Barnes and Noble 1937-1941, 5 items (Box 73)
- Barnett, Robert 1942, 2 items (Box 73)
- Baro, Gene 1951-1954, 10 items (Box 73)
- Baroff, Gene 1947-1949, 13 items (Box 73)
- Barr, Stringfellow 1936-1953, ca. 75 items (Box 73)
- Barret, Leighton 1941, 9 items (Box 73)
- Bartlett, Ruhl 1951, 4 items (Box 73)
- Baruch, Bernard 1929-1954, 7 items (Box 73)
- Barzun, Jacques 1945-1951, 6 items (Box 73)
- Basler, Roy 1937-1943, 8 items (Box 73)
- Basso, Hamilton 1939-1942, 27 items (Box 73)
- Bates, Ernest Sutherland 1937 October 2, 1 l. (Box 73)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Bates
- Bates, Ralph 1941, 9 items (Box 73)
- Bates, Searle 1939-1954, 8 items (Box 73)
- Batista, Fulgencio 1939, 6 items (Box 73)
- Battle, George Gordon 1924-1940, 47 items (Box 73)
- Baxter, James Phinney III 1944-1950, 6 items (Box 73)
- Baxter, James 1948, 2 items (Box 73)
- Beach, Joseph Warren 1938-1953, ca. 70 items (Box 73)
- Beals, Carleton 1936-1949, 14 items (Box 73)
- Beard, Charles Austin 1936-1944, 52 items (Box 73)
- Beard, Miriam 1941, 13 items (Box 73)
- Beaudoin, Kenneth Laurence 1936-1942, 20 items (Box 73)
- Beck, Leslie 1944 July 27, 1 l. (Box 73)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Beck
- Beck, Warren 1941-1954, ca. 80 items (Box 73)
- Becker, Carl 1937-1944, 23 items (Box 73)
- Becker, Edna 1944 July 28, 1 l. (Box 73)
- Beems, Griffith 1938-1947, 14 items (Box 74)
- Beer, Ethel 1936-1952, 44 items (Box 74)
- Behrendt, Walter Curt 1938, 12 items (Box 74)
- Beiswanger, William Frederick 1936-1939, 6 items (Box 74)
- Belitt, Ben 1936-1954, ca. 100 items (Box 74)
- Bell, Landon 1939-1943, 10 items (Box 74)
- Bemis, Samuel Flagg 1942-1952, 39 items (Box 74)
- Benes, Eduard 1938, 2 items (Box 74)
- Benet, James 1940 June 14, 1 l. (Box 74)
  Letter from Virginia Quarterly Review
- Benét, Laura 1944-1946, 2 items (Box 74)
  Letters from Virginia Quarterly Review
- Benét, Stephen Vincent 1938-1940, 2 items (Box 74)
- Benét, William Rose 1935 October 12, 1 l. (Box 74)
- Ben-Horin, Eliahu 1947, 2 items (Box 74)
- Benoit, Gérard 1954, 3 items (Box 74)
- Bent, Silas 1936-1944, 45 items (Box 74)
- Bentley, Eric 1947-1948, 15 items (Box 74)
- Berge, Wendell 1947, 20 items (Box 74)
- Bergin, Thomas 1951-1954, 25 items (Box 74)
- Berkeley, Norborne 1935-1939, 3 items (Box 74)
- Berle, Adolf 1937-1953, 21 items (Box 74)
- Berryman, John 1938-1949, 10 items (Box 74)
- Betts, Thomas Jeffries 1936-1941, 45 items (Box 74)
- Beukema, Herman 1940-1942, 14 items (Box 74)
- Bicknell, John 1951-1954, 26 items (Box 74)
- Bidwell, Percy 1937-1943, 5 items (Box 74)
- Bingham, Barry 1924-1954, 32 items (Box 74)
- Bingham, Blanche 1951, 5 items (Box 74)
- Bingham, Robert Worth 1935 February 25, 1 l. (Box 74)
- Binkley, Robert 1935-1938, 33 items (Box 74)
- Binkley, Wilfred 1946-1954, 14 items (Box 74)
- Birdsall, Paul 1936-1942, 6 items (Box 74)
- Bishko, Charles 1947-1950, 8 items (Box 74)
- Bishop, Elizabeth 1947-1949, 4 items (Box 74)
- Bishop, John Peale 1936-1940, 42 items (Box 74)
- Black, Eugene 1949, 12 items (Box 75)
- Black, Harold Garnet 1942-1951, 10 items (Box 75)
- Black, Helen 1937-1949, 27 items (Box 75)
- Black Star Publishing Company 1936-1937, 18 items (Box 75)
- Blackford, Launcelot Minor 1940-1941, 4 items (Box 75)
- Blackmur, R.P. 1936-1949, ca. 85 items (Box 75)
- Blackstone, Bernard 1949, 2 items (Box 75)
- Blair, Elizabeth Frost 1937, 3 items (Box 75)
- Blanco, Ignacio Matte 1940, 8 items (Box 75)
- Blankner, Frederika 1937-1953, 26 items (Box 75)
- Blanton, Mr. and Mrs. Wyndham 1938-1946, 19 items (Box 75)
- Balssingame, Lurton 1936-1954, ca. 75 items (Box 75)
- Bliven, Bruce 1939-1941, 26 items (Box 75)
- Block, Herbert 1953 September 16, 1 l. (Box 75)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Block
- Boaz, Franz 1939, 2 items (Box 75)
- Bobbs-Merrill Company 1927-1951, 18 items (Box 75)
- Bogan, Louise 1939, 4 items (Box 75)
- Bok, Curtis 1935-1939, 3 items (Box 75)
- Bond, Frederick Drew 1938-1949, 16 items (Box 75)
- Bond, Nelson 1937, 2 items (Box 75)
- Bond, Richmond 1936-1937, 6 items (Box 75)
- Bonner, Amy 1939-1946, 4 items (Box 75)
- Bonthron, Marion 1937-1954, 18 items (Box 75)
- Boocock, Murray 1929-1939, 27 items (Box 75)
- Borah, William 1936 December 16, 1 l. (Box 75)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Borah
- Borroff, Marie 1949-1952, 10 items (Box 75)
- Bose, S.M. 1939 September 27, 1 l. (Box 75)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Bose
- Boudin, Leonard 1939-1940, 12 items (Box 75)
- Bowen, Elizabeth 1945-1954, 5 items (Box 75)
- Bowers, Claude 1933-1948, 17 items (Box 75)
- Bowers, Fredson 1939-1953, 8 items (Box 75)
- Bowers, Nancy Hale 1952 June 20, 1 l. (Box 75)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Nancy Hale Bowers
- Bowles, Chester 1950, 2 items (Box 75)
- Bowling, Lawrence 1941-1950, 13 items (Box 75)
- Bowman, Isaiah 1947-1949, 5 items (Box 75)
- Bowra, C.M. 1948-1949, 2 items (Box 75)
- Boyd, Ernest 1939-1940, 2 items (Box 75)
- Boyd, Julian 1938-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 75)
- Boykin, Clarence 1930-1936, 7 items (Box 75)
- Brace, Gerald Warner 1948 March 22, 1 l. (Box 76)
- Bradford, Curtis 1939-1951, 30 items (Box 76)
- Bradford, Roark 1939, 2 items (Box 76)
- Braibanti, Ralph 1947-1954, 12 items (Box 76)
- Brandeis, Louis Dembitz 1924-1939, 2 items (Box 76)
- Brandt and Brandt 1935-1954, ca. 450 items (Box 76)
- Brant, Irving 1938 March 18, 1 l. (Box 76)
- Brenner, Leah 1944-1953, 42 items (Box 76)
- Brett, Edith 1951, 3 items (Box 76)
- Brickell, Herschell 1935-1951, ca. 75 items (Box 76)
- Bridenbaugh, Carl 1948-1952, 23 items (Box 76)
- Bridgman, Percy 1951, 2 items (Box 76)
- Briggs, Asa 1953-1954, 10 items (Box 76)
- Brinnin, John Malcolm 1938-1946, 30 items (Box 76)
- Brinton, Crane 1936-1954, 73 items (Box 76)
- Brittain, Robert 1949, 4 items (Box 76)
- Brodie, Bernard 1942-1954, ca. 70 items (Box 77)
- Brodie, Fawn 1947, 4 items (Box 77)
- Brogan, Denis William 1936-1953, ca. 75 items (Box 77)
- Bromfield, Louis 1949-1954, 17 items (Box 77)
- Bromsen, Maury 1944, 2 items (Box 77)
- Bronk, Detlev 1950-1951, 3 items (Box 77)
- Bronson, Bertrand 1952, 9 items (Box 77)
- Brooks, Cleanth 1935-1954, 19 items (Box 77)
- Brooks Gwendolyn 1942 September 29, 1 l. (Box 77)
- Brooks, Van Wyck 1934-1944, 13 items (Box 77)
- Broun, Heywood 1935 September 17, 1 l. (Box 77)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Broun
- Curtis Brown, Ltd. 1935-1954, ca. 700 items (Box 77)
- Brown, E. K. 1936-1951, 27 items (Box 78)
- Brown, Ford 1936-1937, 17 items (Box 78)
- Brown, Harry 1838-1945, 19 items (Box 78)
- Brown, Jack 1939, 5 items (Box 78)
- Brown, Kenneth 1943-1952, 9 items (Box 78)
- Brown, Margaret Wise 1939, 3 items (Box 78)
- Brown, Owsley 1935-1938, 9 items (Box 78)
- Brown, Stuart Gerry 1942-1950, 13 items (Box 78)
- Browne, Lewis 1939, 4 items (Box 78)
  Letters, Virginia Quarterly Review to Browne
- Brownlow, Louis 1954 April 5, 1 l. (Box 78)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Brownlow
- Bruce, David 1939-1946, 15 items (Box 78)
- Bruce, William Cabell 1925-1929, 15 items (Box 78)
- Bruening, Heinrich 1938 July 15, 1 l. (Box 78)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Bruening
- Bryan, John 1937-1938, 2 items (Box 78)
  Letters, Virginia Quarterly Review to Bryan
- Bryan, John Stewart 1924-1939, 41 items (Box 78)
- Bryan, Jonathan 1929-1933, 11 items (Box 78)
- Bryant, Arthur 1940, 4 items (Box 78)
- Bryant, Louise Stevens 1939-1940, 45 items (Box 78)
- Buchanan, Scott 1936-1943, 31 items (Box 78)
- Buchler, Justus 1937-1939, 24 items (Box 78)
- Buck, Paul 1951, 2 items (Box 78)
- Buchler, Leslie 1947-1954, 8 items (Box 78)
- Budberg, Baroness 1938-1940, 10 items (Box 78)
- Büell, Raymond Leslie 1936-1944, 15 items (Box 78)
- Buhler, Curt 1950, 10 items (Box 78)
- Bullock, Alan 1953 August 27, 1 l. (Box 78)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Bullock
- Bullock, Helen 1938-1946, 15 items (Box 78)
- Bunche, Ralph 1951-1954, 3 items (Box 78)
- Bundy, McGeorge 1951, 3 items (Box 78)
- Burchard, John 1952-1953, 14 items (Box 78)
- Burgess, W. Randolph 1940-1941, 3 items (Box 78)
- Burgum, Edwin Berry 1941-1949, ca. 75 items (Box 78)
- Burke, Kenneth 1937 December 30, 1 l. (Box 78)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Burke
- Burman, Ben Lucien 1950, 12 items (Box 78)
- Burton, Richard 1937, 2 items (Box 78)
- Bush, Mr. and Mrs. Douglas 1945-1953, 30 items (Box 78)
- Butcher, Fanny 1935-1936, 2 items (Box 78)
  Letters, Virginia Quarterly Review to Butcher
- Butler, David 1953-1954, 14 items (Box 78)
- Butler, Nicholas 1940, 2 items (Box 78)
- Butterfield, Lyman 1950-1954, 21 items (Box 78)
- Bye, George 1942-1950, 32 items (Box 79)
- Bynner, Witter 1925-1940, 8 items (Box 79)
- Byrd, Harry Flood 1935-1954, 6 items (Box 79)
- Byrd, Richard Evelyn 1953 June 10, 1 l. (Box 79)
- Byrne, J. Patrick 1938-1948, 6 items (Box 79)
- Byrnes, James 1948, 2 items (Box 79)
- Miscellaneous B 1935-1954, ca. 1300 items (Box 79 & 80)
- Cahn, Edmond 1952-1953, 22 items (Box 81)
- Cairns, Huntington 1949-1953, 2 items (Box 81)
- Caldwell, Wallace 1937-1938, 8 items (Box 81)
- Calmer, Ned 1945, 9 items (Box 81)
- Cameron, Brodnax 1938-1939, 10 items (Box 81)
- Campbell, Edmund Schureman 1947, 2 items (Box 81)
- Campbell, John 1947-1950, 25 items (Box 81)
- Campbell, Willis 1935-1939, 11 items (Box 81)
- Canaday, John 1942-1953, 48 items (Box 81)
- Canby, Marion 1936-1949, 9 items (Box 81)
- Cane, Melville 1936-1947, 18 items (Box 81)
- Cantwell, Robert 1937 October 2, 1 l. (Box 81)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Cantwell
- Capote, Truman n.d., 1 l. (Box 81)
- Cardenas, Lazaro 1939 May 23, 1 l. (Box 81)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Cardenas
- Carhart, Arthur Hawthorne 1952 September 5, 1 l. (Box 81)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Carhart
- Carleton, William 1946-1954, ca. 75 items (Box 81)
- Carlson, Anton Julius 1941, 19 items (Box 81)
- Carmichael, Joel 1940-1953, 15 items (Box 81)
- Carmichael, Oliver 1954, 2 items (Box 81)
- Carr, Ray 1946-1948, 8 items (Box 81)
- Carrillo, Alejandro 1940, 5 items (Box 81)
- Carruth, Hayden 1948-1951, 16 items (Box 81)
- Carson, Gerald 1954, 18 items (Box 81)
- Carter, Clarence 1938, 10 items (Box 81)
- Carter, Edward 1939-1940, 12 items (Box 81)
- Carter, Hodding 1949-1954, 27 items (Box 81)
- Carter, John 1949-1950, 9 items (Box 81)
- Cassill, Robert Verlin 1954 June 30, 1 l. (Box 81)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Cassill
- Catton, Bruce 1952, 9 items (Box 81)
- Caughey, Elford 1939-1952, 3 items (Box 81)
- Cauthen, Irby 1953, 3 items (Box 81)
- Caxton Printers, Ltd. 1937-1949, 4 items (Box 81)
- Cecil, Lord David 1948 September 21, 1 l. (Box 81)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Cecil
- Century Company 1926-1932, 10 items (Box 81)
- Chaffee, Zechariah 1948-1949, 5 items (Box 81)
- Chalmers, Gordon Keith 1935-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 81)
- Chaloner, John Armstrong 1929-1930, 2 items (Box 81)
  Letters, Virginia Quarterly Review to Chaloner
- Chamberlain, Bernard 1936, 3 items (Box 82)
- Chamberlain, John 1936-1941, 13 items (Box 82)
- Chambers, Lenoir 1936, 2 items (Box 82)
- Chambrun, Jacques 1936-1949, ca. 75 items (Box 82)
- Chandler, Lester 1951, 5 items (Box 82)
- Chandracekhar, Sripati 1943-1944, 14 items (Box 82)
- Chaplin, Charles, Representative of 1938-1939, 6 items (Box 82)
- Chappell, Warren 1938-1941, 25 items (Box 82)
- Chase, Eugene 1941-1954, ca. 60 items (Box 82)
- Chase, Mary Ellen 1941-1949, 6 items (Box 82)
- Chase, Stuart 1937-1943, 7 items (Box 82)
- Chaudhuri, Bhabes Chandra 1950-1952, 8 items (Box 82)
- Chen Han-Seng 1938, 4 items (Box 82)
- Cheney, Frances 1954, 6 items (Box 82)
- Cherrington, Ben 1939, 2 items (Box 82)
- Cherwell, Lord 1945 December 31, 1 l. (Box 82)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Cherwell
- Chew, Samuel 1951, 3 items (Box 82)
- Ch'ao-ting Chi 1939-1940, 30 items (Box 82)
- University of Chicago Press 1928-1953, 17 items (Box 82)
- Childs, James Rives 1939-1953, 2 items (Box 82)
  Letters, to Virginia Quarterly Review
- Childs, Marquis 1948 March 22, 1 l. (Box 82)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Childs
- Chinard, Gilbert 1942-1950, 27 items (Box 82)
- Christie, Margaret 1945-1951, 11 items (Box 82)
- Chubb, Thomas Caldecot 1936-1939, 4 items (Box 82)
- Church, Peggy 1945-1954, 7 items (Box 82)
- Chute, Marchette 1949, 10 items (Box 82)
- Ciechanowski, Jan 1942, 3 items (Box 82)
- Clark, Barrett 1936, 2 items (Box 82)
- Clark, Bennett 1935 June 15, 1 l. (Box 82)
- Clark, Leonard 1953, 3 items (Box 82)
- Clark, Walter Van Tilburg 1941-1952, 11 items (Box 82)
- Clark, William 1941, 10 items (Box 82)
- Clark, William Andrews 1925-1932, 19 items (Box 82)
- Clarke, George Herbert 1940-1944, 19 items (Box 82)
- Cleaton, Allen 1930-1953, 23 items (Box 82)
- Cleghorn, Sarah 1949, 2 items (Box 82)
- Clemens, Cyril 1936-1952, 12 items (Box 82)
- Clemons, Harry 1929-1941, 21 items (Box 82)
- Clopton, Malvern 1935-1939, 12 items (Box 82)
- Clugston, W.G. 1936-1954, 18 items (Box 82)
- Coatsworth, Elizabeth 1947, 4 items (Box 82)
- Coblentz, Stanton Arthur 1936-1950, 4 items (Box 82)
- Cochran, Louis 1954, 4 items (Box 82)
- Cochran, Thomas 1940, 29 items (Box 82)
- Coe, Virginius 1938-1940, 31 items (Box 82)
- Coffin, Robert Peter Tristram 1936-1953, ca. 75 items (Box 83)
- Cohen, Morris 1941-1942, 3 items (Box 83)
- Cohn, David 1954 November 22, 1 l. (Box 83)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Cohn
- Coit, Margaret 1949-1952, 13 items (Box 83)
- Coker, Francis 1936 October 1, 2 l. (Box 83)
  Letter, Virginia Quarterly Review to Coker
- Colby, Bainbridge 1935, 3 items (Box 83)
- Cole, Taylor 1951, 2 items (Box 83)
- Collier, John 1942, 7 items (Box 83)
- Collier, Tarleton 1946-1953, 34 items (Box 83)
- Collins, Carvel 1951-1953, 6 items (Box 83)
- Colum, Padraic 1939-1950, 3 items (Box 83)
- Columbia University Press 1931-1948, 15 items (Box 83)
- Cometti, Elizabeth 1952, 5 items (Box 83)
- Commager, Henry Steele 1942-1943, 9 items (Box 83)
- Compton, Karl 1940-1948, 4 items (Box 83)
- Conant, James Bryant 1935-1952, 19 items (Box 83)
- Condliffe, J.B. 1944, 3 items (Box 83)
- Conkling, Grace Hazard 1949, 2 items (Box 83)
- Conroy, Philip 1938-1939, 2 items (Box 83)
  Letters, Virginia Quarterly Review to Conroy
- Cons, Louis 1938-1939, 9 items (Box 83)
- Convisser, Israel 1954, 10 items (Box 83)
- Cook, Albert 1950-1954, 16 items (Box 83)
- Cooke, Alistair 1952, 2 items (Box 83)
- Corcoran, Thomas 1939, 4 items (Box 83)
- Cordell, Mr. and Mrs. William 1936-1949, 16 items (Box 83)
- Corle, Edwin 1943-1954, 8 items (Box 83)
- Corson, John 1936-1938, 35 items (Box 83)
- Corwin, Edward 1939-1953, 18 items (Box 83)
- Cory, Daniel 1953-1954, 16 items (Box 83)
- Costigan, Edward 1935 June 17, 1 l. (Box 83)
  Letter, to Virginia Quarterly Review
- Cot, Mr. and Mrs. Pierre 1942-1943, 23 items (Box 83)
- Couch, William Terry 1936-1954, ca. 70 items (Box 83)
- Coutler, Ellis Merton 1949, 3 items (Box 83)
- Cournos, John 1935-1938, 31 items (Box 83)
- Cousins, Norman 1941-1946, 4 items (Box 83)
- Couzens, James, Secretary of 1935 June 15, 1 l. (Box 83)
- Covici, Friede, Inc. 1931-1937, 5 items (Box 83)
  Letters, Virginia Quarterly Review to Covici, Friede
- Coward-McCann 1943-1947, 9 items (Box 83)
- Cowley, Malcolm 1938-1945, 8 items (Box 83)
- Coxe, Louis Osborne 1941-1954, 10 items (Box 83)
- Coyle, David Cushman 1936-1954, ca. 85 items (Box 83)
- Crabites, Pierre 1936-1942, 39 items (Box 83)
- Craig, Hardin 1937-1942, 9 items (Box 83)
- Crane, Charles 1935-1939, 18 items (Box 84)
- Crane, Hart 1927 August 7, 1 l. (Box 84)
- Crankshaw, Edward 1953-1954, 9 items (Box 84)
- Craven, Avery 1937-1954, ca. 50 items (Box 84)
- Craven, Wesley Frank 1942-1946, 9 items (Box 84)